人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  小舞
翻译 猪猪
翻译 送小孩
翻译 尼克白
翻译  泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家幸福筒
时间轴 imok
时间轴 崽猪
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
特效/后期 吉吉·波顿
特效/后期 拉图
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第七集
我为你做了交易  保你不知感恩的脑袋
I made a deal for you to keep your ungrateful head
在你不知感恩的颈项上多留一阵
on your ungrateful neck a little while longer.
抱歉  我有什么好感恩的
I'm sorry, what am I grateful for?
感激为没犯过的罪受罚
The opportunity to live and die at the Wall
获得终老绝境长城的机会吗
as punishment for a crime I did not commit?
你断送了自己的生机  活生生断送了
You threw your life away. You threw it away.
这不是玩笑  你明白的吧
It's not a joke. You understand that, don't you?
这当然是个玩笑  只是不太好笑而已
Of course it's a joke, just not a very funny one.
我不能...
I couldn't--
我听不下去了
I couldn't listen to her
她就站在那儿说谎
standing there telling her lies.
我做不到
I couldn't do it.
你爱上了一个妓女
You fell in love with a whore.
是的  我爱上了一个妓女
Yes, I fell in love with a whore.
还愚蠢地以为她也爱上了我
And I was stupid enough to think that she had fallen in love with me.
你做的交易
That deal you made,
正中父亲下怀
it was everything Father wanted.
你也知道的吧
You do see that?
你回去给他做继承人
He gets you back as his heir.
未来的凯岩城公爵
The future Lord of the Rock.
我则被送去黑城堡
And he ships me off to Castle Black,
终于滚出他的视线
out of sight at last.
如此完美
All so perfect.
打破他的如意算盘感觉真不错
It felt good to take that from him.
他明知我无罪  却乐意牺牲我
He knows I'm innocent and he's willing to sacrifice me anyway.
他可以牺牲我们任何人
He's willing to sacrifice any of us.
除了你
Not you.
你是家里的宝贝疙瘩
You're the golden son.
你可以宰了国王  丢一只手
You could kill a king, lose a hand,
操自己老姐  可你仍然是宝贝疙瘩
fuck your own sister, you'll always be the golden son.
小心了
Careful.
我是你最后一个朋友
I'm the last friend you've got.
至少我还能当场揭露他们的真面目
At least I got to tell them what they really are.
是啊  慷慨激昂的演说
Yes, brilliant speech.
够他们议论好多天
They'll be talking about it for days to come.
我还以为你是个现实的人
I thought you were a realist.
没想到你会死于傲慢
Didn't realize you'd die for pride.
先别对我放弃希望
Don't give up on me just yet.
上次比武审判我死里逃生
I survived one trial by combat,
即便你没能赶去救我
even though you weren't there to save me.
这次我也救不了你
I can't save you this time either.
训练已经证明
My training has proved
我用左手连个马棚小子也打不过
that I can't beat a stable boy with my left hand.
你的冒险精神哪儿去了
Where's your sense of adventure?
就算你输了  想象一下你倒地时父亲的表情
Even if you lose, imagine the look on Father's face when you fall.
我们的家族英名  一剑之下灰飞烟灭
Our family name snuffed out with a single swing of the sword.
令人向往
It is tempting.
波隆曾经代我出战  这次他也会去
Bronn fought for me once, he'll do it again.
如果他赢了
If he wins,
我一辈子都要欠他的债咯
I expect I'll be in his debt for the rest of my life.
如果他能赢
If he wins.
能替我找他来吗
Will you find him for me?
瑟曦打算选谁做代理骑士
Who does Cersei plan on naming as a champion?
希望是马林·特兰爵士
I hope it's Ser Meryn Trant.
我会很乐意看波隆给这殴打孩童的傲慢货开膛
I'd enjoy watching Bronn disembowel that pompous child beater.
不
No.
不是马林爵士
Not Ser Meryn.
去  上
Go on, move it.
还有你
And you.
上
Come on.
饶命
Mercy.
求求您
Please.
求您饶命
Please, mercy.
格雷果爵士  欢迎来到君临
Ser Gregor. Welcome to the capital.
感谢你随召而至
Thank you for riding here so quickly.
你看上去状态不错
You seem to be in good form.
我跟谁打
Who am I fighting?
有关系吗
Does it matter?
可能有吃的
Could be food.
可能有士兵
Could be soldiers.
你不该这样坐在外边
You shouldn't be sitting out here like this.
还能去哪儿坐
Where else to sit?
我试过走回棚屋
Tried to walk back to my hut,
可是太疼了
hurt too much.
然后我想起来  棚屋已经给他们烧了
Then I remembered they burned my hut down.
"他们"是什么人
Who were "they"?
我早就不去问啦
I stopped asking a while ago.
你这伤好不了了
That's not gonna get better.
看样子也不像
Doesn't seem so.
这样上路很痛苦
A bad way to go.
你还没受够吗
Haven't you had enough?
受够什么
Of what?
我知道
I know.
该上路了
Time to go.
自己做个了断
Take matters into my own hands.
我有过这个念头
The thought has occurred to me.
那还坚持什么
So why go on?
习惯
Habit.
再没什么比这更糟了
Nothing could be worse than this.
或许"没什么"比这更糟
Maybe nothing is worse than this.
"没什么"不比任何事好  也不比任何事坏
Nothing isn't better or worse than anything.
"没什么"就是什么都没有
Nothing is just nothing.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫艾莉亚
My name is Arya.
艾莉亚·史塔克
Arya Stark.
你是她父亲
You her father?
我是她的俘虏者
Her captor.
带她去找她姨妈要赎金
Bringing her to her aunt for ransom.
那也是公平交换
A fair exchange, that is.
我做生意向来讲究公平交易
Always held to the notion of fair exchange in all my dealings.
你给我  我给你
You give me, I give you.
公平
Fair.
平衡
A balance.
平衡也不复存在啦
No balance anymore.
能给口喝的吗
Could I have a drink?
等死让人嗓子干
Dying is thirsty work.
要是酒就好了
Wish it were wine.
我也想
So do I.
那是心脏的位置
That's where the heart is.
那是杀人的方法
That's how you kill a man.
你们干什么
The fuck you doing?
你的人头能换钱
There's a price on your head.
叫国王去吃屎  他果然就悬赏你的人头
Guess that's what the king does when you tell him to fuck off.
国王死啦
The king's dead.
在自己的婚宴上喝了毒酒
He drank poisoned wine at his own wedding.
你的罪名是杀害兰尼斯特士兵
The bounty on you is for killing Lannister soldiers.
一百银鹿
100 silver stags.
你以为自己能领到赏钱咯
And you thought you were going to collect it?
没过脑子是吧
Didn't think very hard, did you?
尤伦带我去长城时  你们是他的囚犯
You were Yoren's prisoners when he was taking me to the Wall.
那时他说要用棍子操我
He told me he'd fuck me bloody with a stick.
今天跟你盘算的不一样吧
This day's really not working out the way you planned.
他也在你的名单里吗
He on your little list?
不可能
He can't be.
我不知道他的名字
I don't know his name.
你叫什么
What's your name?
-罗尔杰  -谢谢
- Rorge. - Thank you.
学得很快
You're learning.
游骑兵归来
Rangers returning!
他们回来了
They return!
-游骑兵归来  -你们好啊
- Rangers returning! - Greetings.
真没想到还能再见到你
Didn't think I'd see you again.
还好吗  琼恩
All right, Jon?
欢迎回来  兄弟
Welcome back, brother.
雪诺大人
Lord Snow.
这里不是养野兽的地方
This is no place for wild beasts.
把它关起来
Lock him away
否则我叫哈布扔进今晚的炖汤
or I'll let Hobb throw him in tonight's stew.
过来  白灵
Come on, Ghost.
我们离开的时候  曼斯大军逼近卡斯特堡垒
Mance's army was closing in on Craster's Keep when we left.
我们在欧斯里克山看到了他们的营火
We saw their campfires from Osric's Hill.
下个满月前  他们就会到达长城
They'll reach the Wall before the next full moon.
我倒是纳闷你怎么不过去打个招呼呀
I'm surprised you didn't ride over and say hello.
塞外之王是你的老朋友吧
The King-beyond-the-Wall is your old friend, isn't he?
我们该做好准备
We need to prepare.
我们一直在准备
We've been preparing.
我们应该封锁隧道
We should seal the tunnel.
用石头和冰块堵上
Plug it with rocks and ice.
灌上水  冰冻起来
Flood it and let it freeze.
那我们怎么往北去侦察
And how would we range north?
-不去  -懦夫
- We wouldn't. - Coward.
你砍断我们的双腿
You would cut off our legs,
挖出我们的眼珠
pluck out our eyes,
让我们畏缩在长城背后
leave us cowering behind the Wall
以期风暴过去吗
hoping for the storm to pass?
十万大军来袭  我们守不住门的
We can't defend the gate against 100,000 men.
这座城堡已经伫立了数千年
This castle has stood for thousands of years.
守夜人军团也守卫了她数千年
The Night's Watch has defended her for thousands of years.
多少世纪以来  我们从没封锁过隧道
And in all those centuries, we have never sealed the tunnel.
您见过巨人吗  艾里沙爵士
Have you ever seen a giant, Ser Alliser?
我见过
I have.
隧道和大门根本阻挡不了他们
The tunnels, the gates won't stop them.
大门上的铁栅有四吋之粗
The bars on those gates are four inches thick.
精钢打造
Cold-rolled steel.
那也阻挡不了
They won't stop them.
提醒我一下  你属于什么岗位  雪诺大人
Remind me which order you belong to, Lord Snow.
事务官
The stewards.
维护隧道是事务官的职责吗
Are the stewards responsible for maintaining the tunnel?
不是
No.
那是谁的职责
Who would that be?
-工匠  -没错  是工匠
- The builders. - Ah, the builders.
首席工匠亚威克
First Builder Yarwyck,
雪诺大人建议封闭隧道
Lord Snow here recommends sealing the tunnel,
使我们无法履行
leaving us unable to carry out our duties
守夜人军团的誓言
as sworn brothers of the Night's Watch.
你同意吗
Do you agree with him?
不
No.
鉴于你对野人军队的深度了解  雪诺大人
Given your deep knowledge of the wildling army, Lord Snow,
从今天起到满月前  你和塔利负责
you and Tarly will take night duties atop the Wall
在长城上守夜
until the full moon.
好了
Moving on.
首席工匠  我们需要
First Builder, we'll need
带一百桶沥青到长城上
100 barrels of pitch brought atop the wall.
大人
My lord.
你有新衣服了
You have new clothes.
你喜欢吗
Do you like 'em? Eh?
手套是鹿皮的
Gloves are doeskin.
比处女的大腿还软和
Softer than a virgin's thighs.
过了这么多天你才来
I sent for you days ago.
-我有点忙  -忙什么
- I've been a bit busy. - Doing what?
我孤家寡人的日子要结束了
My lonesome bachelor days are over.
我要和洛丽丝·史铎克渥斯成亲
I'm to wed Lollys Stokeworth.
洛丽丝·史铎克渥斯
Lollys Stokeworth?
我不觉得她是你喜欢的类型
She doesn't strike me as your sort of girl.
不能说我只喜欢哪种女人
I wouldn't say I had a single sort of girl.
她分明是个痴呆
She's dim-witted.
我想要天才  就该娶你了
If I wanted wits, I'd marry you.
我老姐安排这桩姻缘的时候
When my sister arranged this love match,
她提起过洛丽丝有个姐姐吗
did she mention that Lollys has an older sister?
法丽丝
Falyse.
没错  我知道有这么个姐姐
Aye, I did know about the older sister.
那你也了解继承顺序吧
And you understand the rules of inheritance?
法丽丝四十岁  无子
Falyse is 40 and barren.
等她父亲过世  史铎克渥斯堡还是她的
She still gets Castle Stokeworth when her father dies.
是的
She does.
她死在她父亲之前就不会了
Unless she happens to perish before her father.
那洛丽丝就能继承城堡
Then Lollys gets the castle.
怎么  女士们从马上摔落
What? Ladies fall from their horses
跌断了她们漂亮的脖子  这种事时有发生
and snap their pretty necks all the time.
你和我老姐还真是绝配
You and my sister deserve each other.
既然如此  你为什么还来
Why did you bother to come here?
因为你说过  哪天有人要我出卖你
You once said if anyone ever asked me to sell you out,
你付双倍的价钱
you'd double their price.
你要两个老婆还是两座城堡
Is it two wives you want or two castles?
一样一个就行
One of each will do.
但如果你要我去杀魔山
But if you want me to kill the Mountain for you,
这城堡非得是个大家伙
it'd better be a damn big castle.
眼下我无法提供城堡
I'm a bit short on castles at the moment.
但你可以得到我的金子和谢意
But I can offer you gold and gratitude.
金子我有
I have gold.
我拿你的谢意能做什么呢
What can I buy with gratitude?
总有一天我会报答你
You might be surprised.
兰尼斯特有债必还
A Lannister always pays his debts.
你老姐不也是个兰尼斯特
Your sister's a Lannister, too.
我老婆是临冬城的继承人
My wife is heir to Winterfell.
只要我能安然度过此劫
If I emerge from this with my head still on my shoulders,
说不定有一天我会以她的名义统治北境
I may one day rule the North in her name.
到时候你要什么有什么
I could carve you out a big piece of it.
只要  有一天  到时候
If and may and could.
北地实在太他妈的冷
It's bloody cold up north.
洛丽丝却是暖和柔软
Lollys is soft and warm.
看得见摸得着
And close.
要是让你在与魔山打架
If I gave you the choice between fucking Lollys
和操洛丽丝之间作选择  只怕连眼都不眨
and fighting the Mountain, you'd have your britches down
你就脱好裤子  掏出家伙了
and your cock out before I could blink.
你这么怕他
Does he frighten you so much?
不怕他才怪  你当我是白痴
I'd be a bloody fool if he didn't frighten me.
他壮得惊人  臂力无穷
He's freakish big and freakish strong.
就那般体格的人而言  他的速度相当可怕
And quicker than you'd expect for a man of that size.
也许我能赢
Maybe I could take him,
一直围着他转圈
dance around until he's so tired
直到他连剑也举不动
of hacking at me, he dropped his sword,
再废掉他的腿
get him off his feet somehow.
可只要一个失误
But one misstep...
我就没命
...and I'm dead.
我凭什么去冒险
Why should I risk it?
因为你是我的朋友
Because you're my friend.
对  我是你的朋友
Aye, I'm your friend.
但你几时拿性命为我冒险过
And when have you ever risked your life for me?
我喜欢你
I like you,
喜欢你这出身娇贵的小无赖
pampered little shit that you are.
但我更喜欢自己
I just like myself more.
我理解
I understand.
走到这一步我很抱歉
I'm sorry it has to be this way.
为什么道歉
Why are you sorry?
为你是个没有良心  心狠手辣的流氓吗
Because you're an evil bastard with no conscience and no heart?
我起初欣赏的就是你这点
That's what I liked about you in the first place.
与你相处很是愉快
We had some good days together.
没错
Yes, we did.
你打算怎么办
What will you do?
大概得亲自上阵宰掉魔山了
I suppose I'll have to kill the Mountain myself.
让歌手们写首伟大的歌谣
Won't that make for a great song?
希望我以后能听到
I hope to hear them sing it one day.
你是怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
您的正门戒备森严
Your door is well guarded,
可窗户没人守
but your window is not.
我游到一哩外的海岛采来这些花
I swam to an island a mile offshore for these.
别再这么做了
Don't do that again.
居然有女人不喜欢野花
Never met a woman who didn't like wildflowers.
这是我的私人住所
These are my private quarters.
需要你的话  我自会召你来的
If I want you here, I will summon you.
原谅我  女王陛下  我的使命就是服侍您
Forgive me, my queen. I live to serve you.
说吧  你为什么过来
Tell me why you're here.
我想求您帮个忙
I came to ask a favor.
我生平只擅长两件事
I only have two talents in this world--
打仗和找女人
war and women.
您要留下来统治弥林
You are staying here in Meereen to rule.
这决定很明智  我尊重您的选择
That is a wise decision. I respect it.
但在弥林  我无处施展才华
But here in Meereen, I cannot pursue my talents.
我已下令让次子团去巡街
I've ordered the Second Sons to patrol the streets
阻止报复性的杀戮
to stop the revenge killing.
您这是让我们当守夜人
You've ordered us to be night watchmen.
至于女人
And as for women,
弥林有成千上万的女人供你追求
there are thousands in Meereen you can pursue.
只有一人
There is only one,
她却不想要我
and she does not want me.
你曾发誓效忠于我
You swore me your sword.
我的剑任您驱使  直到我死
My sword is yours till the day I die.
那么如果我命令你留在弥林巡街
So if I command you to stay in Meereen
你怎么做
and patrol the streets?
那我便留在弥林巡街
I'll stay in Meereen and patrol the streets.
请派我杀掉您的敌人
Send me to kill your enemies.
不管是谁  不论他们身在何方
Any enemy anywhere.
让我施展才华
Let me do what I do best.
很好
Very well.
那便施展你的才华
Do what you do best.
脱掉衣服
Take off your clothes.
请进来  王后
Come in, my queen. Please.
我无意打扰您  女士
I didn't mean to disturb you, my lady.
你我不谈打扰二字
You could never disturb me.
我只是想在出发前跟您谈谈
I just wanted to speak with you before we left.
能帮我把那个小瓶子拿来吗
Could you bring me that vial over there?
蓝色的
The blue one.
不  不是那瓶
No, no, no. Not that one.
你还是永远别碰那瓶为好
You don't even want to touch that one.
旁边的
Next to it.
就是这瓶
That's the one.
今早我向火焰中望去
When I looked into the flames this morning,
真主对我发话了
the Lord spoke to me.
他说
He said,
"今后你难得有机会泡澡  今晚是最后一次
"Tonight, you will have your last good bath in a long while.
好好享受"
Make it count."
笑话而已
A joke.
怕是讲得很拙劣
Not a very good one, I'm afraid.
很有趣  我...
It was. I--
我不太懂幽默
humor isn't my strength.
因为笑话大多是谎言
That's because most jokes are lies
而你信奉真理
and you're devoted to the truth.
女士  既然是谎言  闭口不讲岂非最好
If they're lies, my lady, aren't they best avoided?
不一定
Not always.
这些粉末和药剂
Most of these powders and potions
大都是谎言
are lies.
它们制造幻觉  令人以为见识了真主的力量
Deceptions to make men think they witnessed our Lord's power.
他们一旦步入真主的光辉之中
Once they step into his light,
就会明白这些谎言的意义
they will see the lie for what it was--
不过是引领他们走向真理的把戏
The trick that led them to the truth.
在篝火中加一撮这种粉末
A pinch of this powder in a bonfire
便有一道火柱发出尖啸  冲向天空
will send a flaming column screaming towards the sky.
这瓶则可以造出黑烟
And this one creates a black smoke
最勇敢的人都会被吓到失禁
that will make the bravest man piss himself with fear.
而往任何男人的酒里加一滴这种药剂
And a drop of this in any man's wine
他势必欲火焚身
will drive him wild with lust.
您给史坦尼斯用过吗
Did you use it with Stannis?
没有
No.
别难过
Don't be upset.
男人从不渴求已经拥有的东西
Men never crave what they already have.
肉体之欢罢了
It's only flesh.
正常的需求而已
It needs what it needs.
效忠于真主的任何行为
No act done in service of the Lord
都不能称其为罪孽
can ever be called a sin.
我每天都感谢真主把您带到我们身边
I thank God every day for bringing you to us.
让史坦尼斯遇到您
And Stannis to you.
他想带希琳跟我们一起走
He wants to bring Shireen with us.
我觉得这个想法欠妥
I think that would be ill-advised.
您很清楚  我女儿有异教倾向
My daughter has heretical tendencies, as you're well aware.
我不明白她是真有疑惑  还是故意刁难我
I don't know if her doubt is real or simply meant to spite me,
不过无论如何  她都应该待在家里
but whichever the case, she should stay home.
我明白你的感受
I understand how you feel.
但那是不可能的
But that is impossible.
为什么
Why?
你不需要粉末和药剂  王后
You don't need powders and potions, my queen.
你不需要谎言
You don't need lies.
你足够强大  可以看光之王的火焰
You are strong enough to look into the Lord's light
亲自领会他的真理
and see his truth for yourself.
无论它有多残酷
However harsh it is.
无论它是多么晦涩难懂
However hard for us to understand.
你不需要我的帮助
You don't need my help,
不过很快我就需要你帮忙了
but I will need yours soon.
我们出海时  一定要带上你的女儿
When we set sail, your daughter must be with us.
真主需要她
The Lord needs her.
安达尔人乔拉
Jorah the Andal.
你来觐见女王吗
Are you here to see our queen?
她心情很好
She's in a good mood.
卡丽熙
Khaleesi.
-你来得很早  -比某人来得晚
- You're here early. - Later than some.
你不赞成
You don't approve?
不是赞成与否的问题  而是信任与否的问题
It's not a question of approval, it's a question of trust.
你既不赞成也不信任
You neither approve nor trust.
当然了  他是个佣兵
Why would I? The man's a sellsword.
在效忠我哥哥之前
Didn't you fight for the Golden Company
你不也为黄金团作战吗
before pledging your sword to my brother?
是的
I did.
我信任你
I trust you.
达里奥·纳哈里斯厌倦了团长们发号施令
Daario Naharis killed his captains and dumped their heads at your feet
就杀了他们  将人头丢在您脚下
when he grew tired of their commands.
您怎么能信任这种人
How could you ever have faith in a man like that?
我绝不会信任达里奥这种人
I could never have faith in a man like Daario.
所以我派他和次子团夺回渊凯
That's why I've sent him and the Second Sons to retake Yunkai.
-您已经下令了  -是的
- You have? - I have.
可是  卡丽熙  没有您的统治
Without you there to rule, Khaleesi,
恐怕贤主们只会静待时机
I fear the masters will simply bide their time,
等他们走后重夺控制权
wait for the invaders to leave and reassert control.
所以我命令达里奥
That is why I've ordered Daario
处决渊凯的所有贤主
to execute every master in Yunkai.
贤主们将婴儿从母亲怀中夺走
The masters tear babies from their mothers' arms.
他们残害了成百上千的男童
They mutilate little boys by the thousands.
他们训练少女取悦老人
They train little girls in the art of pleasuring old men.
他们待人如猪狗  这是你说的
They treat men like beasts, as you said yourself.
成百上千地将贤主们
Herding the masters into
赶进围栏  然后宰杀
pens and slaughtering them by the thousands
同样是待人如猪狗
is also treating men like beasts.
您解放的那些奴隶们
The slaves you freed,
他们只懂得以暴易暴
brutality is all they've ever known.
如果您想让他们开化
If you want them to know something else,
就必须亲身示范
you'll have to show it to them.
用什么回报奴隶主呢  仁慈吗
And repay the slavers with what? Kindness?
罚金  严厉的警告
A fine? A stern warning?
人们都乐于将敌方斥为邪恶
It's tempting to see your enemies as evil, all of them,
可是任何战争的任何一方都是善恶相苞
but there's good and evil on both sides in every war ever fought.
是非正邪  让祭司们去争辩罢
Let the priests argue over good and evil.
人奴役人是真实存在的
Slavery is real.
我可以终结它  我必将终结它
I can end it. I will end it.
我也必将消灭那些罪魁祸首
And I will end those behind it.
我曾贩卖过奴隶  卡丽熙
I sold men into slavery, Khaleesi.
而现在  你正在协助我解放他们
And now you are helping me show them to freedom.
如果奈德·史塔克待我如同您
I wouldn't be here to help you if Ned Stark had done to me
对待渊凯的贤主们一样  我不可能来协助您
what you want to do to the masters of Yunkai.
前几天向我请愿埋葬父亲的那个人
The man who came to me the other day about burying his father.
西茨达拉·佐·洛拉克
Hizdahr zo Loraq?
他将作为我的使节
He will accompany the Second Sons
与次子团一同前往渊凯
and serve as my ambassador to Yunkai.
他会告诉贤主们弥林发生了什么
He will tell the masters what has happened in Meereen.
他会说明他们所面临的选择
He will explain the choice they have before them.
活在我统治的新世界
They can live in my new world
或者死在他们的旧世界
or they can die in their old one.
趁达里奥没走  去找他吧
Well, go and catch Daario before he leaves.
告诉他我改主意了
Tell him I changed my mind.
遵命  卡丽熙
Yes, Khaleesi.
不
No.
告诉他是你让我改了主意
Tell him you changed my mind.
妈逼
Rat cunts.
贱婊子
Fucking whore.
你的做法不对
You're doing it wrong.
你应该烧掉破损的皮肉
You need to burn away that horrible bit there.
不然会感染化脓的
Otherwise it's gonna get infected and fester.
我知道你怕火  但如果处理不当...
I know you don't like fire, but if you don't do it right--
不要火
No fire.
一下就好
It'll only take a second.
-没那么疼  -不要火
- It won't hurt that much. - No fire!
别说了
Shut up about it.
什么也别说了
Shut up about everything.
托你的福  在兰尼斯特家的地盘上
Thanks to you, I'm a walking bag of silver
我就像一袋明晃晃的银币
anywhere the Lannisters hold sway.
从这儿到我们要去的地方  无论哪儿
Which is everywhere between where we are now
全是他们的地盘
and where we're going.
我就跟你在村里刺死的那头猪猡一样蠢
I'm as stupid as that hog you stuck back in the village,
害自个儿浑身是伤  还被咬了
getting myself cut and stabbed and bitten.
再丰厚的赎金也不值得冒这么大的险
No reward is worth this much trouble.
真希望我没瞧见你
Wish I'd never laid eyes on you.
你说你哥哥给了你那把剑
You say your brother gave you that sword.
我哥哥给了我这个
My brother gave me this.
就跟你刚才说的一样
It was just like you said a while back.
他把我的脸按到火堆里
Pressed me to the fire
当作鲜嫩多汁的肉排给烤了
like I was a nice juicy mutton chop.
为什么
Why?
他以为我偷了他的玩具
Thought I stole one of his toys.
我没偷  只是拿来玩玩
I didn't steal it. I was just playing with it.
疼得要死
The pain was bad.
气味更糟
The smell was worse.
但最糟的是  下手的是我哥哥
But the worst thing was that it was my brother who did it.
父亲护着他
My father, who protected him...
对别人说是我床单着了火
told everyone my bedding caught fire.
你以为只有你是一个人吗
You think you're on your own?
至少让我洗洗
Let me wash it out
帮你缝合
and help you sew it up at least.
稍微享受享受又不碍事
Bit of comfort never hurt anyone.
过去几周我们都睡在沟里
We've been sleeping in ditches the last few weeks.
今晚可以舒舒服服地睡一次羽毛床
I think we can treat ourselves to a featherbed for the night
吃一顿不是你做的热饭
and a hot meal not cooked by you.
完全赞同  小姐
Couldn't agree more, my lady.
但别指望丝绸内衣了
Just don't start expecting silk underclothes.
你现在不侍奉以前那位大人了
Not working for your former lord any longer.
-好的  小姐  -别喝醉了
- Yes, my lady. - Don't get drunk.
好的  小姐
No, my lady.
你们还要什么吗
Can I get you anything else?
不  足够了  谢谢你
No, this will do nicely, thank you.
腰子派很可口
Kidney pie is wonderful.
谢谢夸奖
Thanks.
我尽力而为
I do my best.
腰子派好吃的秘诀全在材料本身
A good kidney pie is all about the ingredients.
面粉  猪油  水  鸡蛋  牛奶
Flour, lard, water, eggs, milk.
这些都很简单  但是肉
Easy enough. But the meat,
无论平时还是战时  牛腱子肉
peacetime or not, getting your hands on a good bottom round steak
和牛犊腰子都很难搞到
and calves' kidneys is not easy.
有些人拿老牛腰子充数
I mean, some people settle for plain old beef kidneys.
他们没资格做菜
Got no right to cook anything, them.
还有卤汁
Oh, and the gravy.
一说起卤汁我就停不住
Don't get me started on the gravy.
很难调的
Very difficult to get right.
很多人直接放弃卤汁了
See, a lot of people give up on the gravy.
卤汁绝对不可以放弃啊
You cannot give up on the gravy.
卤汁乃好派之母
No gravy, no pie.
就这么简单
Simple as that.
这身盔甲不错  你是骑士吗
That's nice armor. Are you a knight?
不是
No.
穿盔甲的一般都是骑士
Oh, it's just people with armor are usually knights.
通常来说都是  你是从君临来的对吧
Generally speaking. From King's Landing, though, aren't you?
我以前也住那里  跳蚤窝土生土长
From there myself originally. Flea Bottom born and bred.
你们为什么来这里
What brings you to these parts?
我们在找人
We're looking for someone.
谁啊  也许他们来过这里
Someone in particular? Maybe they came in here.
来这里的人很多  前几天有十七个...
A lot of people come in here. Just the other day we had 17--
一个漂亮的高个子红发女孩
A girl, tall, red hair, very pretty.
她叫珊莎·史塔克  但她也许使用了化名
Her name is Sansa Stark, but she may be using a different name.
史塔克家
Starks?
是冥冬城的那家吗
What, like them lot from "Winterhell"?
没有  我没见过
No, ain't seen anyone like that.
听说他们都是叛徒
I heard they was all traitors.
这里不欢迎叛徒
Don't need no traitors in here.
我曾效忠他们的母亲凯特琳·史塔克
I pledged my life to their mother Catelyn Stark.
我向她发过誓要带她的女儿们回家
I swore to her I'd bring her daughters home.
你真的不要腰子派了吗
Sure I can't get you a bit more kidney pie?
怎么了
What?
没事  小姐
It's nothing, my lady.
如果真没事  你就不会皱着一张脸了
You wouldn't be screwing your face up like that if it was nothing.
我不想冒犯您  小姐  真的不想
Don't want to offend, my lady. Truly, I don't.
你这人无趣得紧  冒犯不来人
You're not interesting enough to be offensive.
兰尼斯特家在找珊莎夫人
The Lannisters want Lady Sansa.
兰尼斯特家有的是钱
The Lannisters have money.
很多人为了钱杀人
People kill for money.
我觉得还是不要告诉别人
I don't think we should be telling people
我们在找珊莎夫人为好
we're searching for Lady Sansa.
小姐  大人  我能跟你们谈谈吗
My lady. My lord. Could I have a word?
谈什么  别又是什么腰子派
What about? Not kidney pie.
您看着是位贵族小姐
You seem like a proper lady.
是值得信任的人
Someone who could be trusted.
我从没见过珊莎·史塔克
I never met no Sansa Stark.
但我认识她妹妹...
But I know her sister...
艾莉亚
Arya.
自从她父亲身首异处之后
No one's seen Arya Stark
就再没人见过艾莉亚·史塔克了
since her father was beheaded.
大家都认为她死了
She's presumed dead.
反正她上次和我说话时还活得好好的
She weren't when I last spoke to her.
-那是什么时候的事  -和守夜人一起北上
- When was that? - Heading up north with the Night's Watch.
她打扮得像个小子
She was all dressed up as a boy.
跟小姐您一样  只是没有盔甲
Like your ladyship, only without the armor.
她化名为阿利
Going by the name Arry.
-她怎么了  -那要...
- So what happened to her? - Well--
说重点
The quick version.
兰尼斯特抓走了我们
The Lannisters took us prisoner.
后来我们逃了出来
We escaped.
又被兄弟会给抓了
The Brotherhood took us prisoner.
他们把我卖给旅店老板
They sold me to the innkeep.
还准备把艾莉亚和另一个人
They were gonna sell Arya to her mother at Riverrun
卖给当时她在奔流城的母亲
along with another prisoner.
那是个丑八怪  满嘴脏话
Big ugly fellow. Foul mouth
半边脸像是被烤成半熟的火腿
and a face like a half-burnt ham.
-凶巴巴的  -是猎狗
- Not friendly. - The Hound.
就是他
That's the one.
如果你找到她  能把这个交给她吗
If you find her, could you give her this?
她很喜欢我上次送她那块
She liked the last one I gave her,
不过这次的做得更好
but, well, this one turned out better.
你刚才说什么来着
Um, you were saying?
她母亲死了  外祖父也死了
Her mother's dead, grandfather's dead,
瓦德·佛雷成了奔流城的新城主
Walder Frey is the new lord of Riverrun.
兄弟会肯定不会去奔流城
The Brotherhood isn't going to Riverrun.
他们会把她带去鹰巢城  小姐
They'll take her to the Eyrie, my lady.
为什么是鹰巢城
Why the Eyrie?
她姨妈  莱莎·艾林
Her aunt, Lysa Arryn.
凯特琳·史塔克的妹妹
Catelyn Stark's sister.
她是艾莉亚唯一还在世的有钱亲戚了
She's Arya's last living relative with money.
而且她对兰尼斯特恨之入骨
She hates the Lannisters.
提利昂大人逼着我学习
Lord Tyrion made sure I knew
各大家族之间的恩恩怨怨
which house married which and who hated who.
珊莎也有可能在那儿
Sansa could be there, too.
是的  小姐
Aye, my lady.
有可能
Could be.
你确定吗
You sure about this?
不确定
No.
我还以为你这时候早就回妓院了
I imagined you'd be back at the brothel at this hour.
几天前
I did spend some time
确实有个貌若天仙的金发美人陪过我
with an absolutely stunning blonde the other day.
快说说
Mm, do tell.
这地牢什么肮脏玩意都有
I've got every kind of filth down here
唯独缺我最爱的那档子下流事
except the kind I like.
我说的是你老姐
Your sister.
瑟曦来找我
Cersei approached me.
我们谈了很多有关她女儿的事情
We spoke a great deal about her daughter.
你老姐对她很是牵挂
How worried your sister is about her.
她费尽心思
She was trying very hard to pretend
假装不是来要我针对你
she had not come to sway me against you.
我认为她自己都信了
I think she may have even believed it herself.
真情流露  以行虚伪之事
Making honest feelings do dishonest work
是她的众多天赋之一
is one of her many gifts.
对她来说  要隐藏真正的意图并不容易
It was difficult for her to hide her true intentions.
很少见到有兰尼斯特
It is rare to meet a Lannister
像我这么热衷于弄死兰尼斯特
who shares my enthusiasm for dead Lannisters.
她一心只想你死
She desperately wants to see you killed.
那她没必要去麻烦你
She didn't need to bother you.
看来我已经自己断送了小命
It looks as though I've taken care of that myself.
等我身首异处  她定然喜不自胜
The joy she will feel when my head leaves my neck.
毕竟她期待已久
She's wanted this for a long time.
我知道
Yes, I know.
我们见过面
We met, you and I.
很多年前
Many years ago.
那我应该记得才对
I think I would have remembered that.
不太可能  因为你那时候刚出生
Unlikely. You had just been born.
我父亲带着我和我姐伊莉亚
Our father brought me and my sister Elia with him
拜访凯岩城
on a visit to Casterly Rock.
那是我第一次离开多恩
My first time away from Dorne.
我对凯岩城的一切都不喜欢
I didn't like anything about the Rock.
食物  天气
Not the food, not the weather,
还有口音
not your accents.
没一样好的
Nothing.
但最让人失望的
But the biggest disappointment...
要数你
you.
那么你和我家人怕是颇有共识
You and my family have more in common than you might admit.
从多恩来的一路上
The whole way from Dorne
大家都在讨论泰温·兰尼斯特家
all anyone talked about was the monster
刚刚出生的那个怪胎
that had been born to Tywin Lannister.
头有身子两倍大
A head twice the size of his body,
双腿间还长了条尾巴
a tail between his legs,
有爪子  还有一只红眼睛
claws, one red eye,
胯下有男人的命根子和女子的阴道
the privates of both a girl and a boy.
那倒省了不少麻烦
That would have made things so much easier.
我们见到你老姐时  她答应带我们去看你
When we met your sister, she promised she would show you to us.
我们每天都在问
Every day we would ask.
但她只是说  "快了"
Every day she would say, "Soon."
后来她和你老哥
Then she and your brother
带我们去了你的婴儿房
took us to your nursery and...
揭开了神秘怪胎的面纱
she unveiled the freak.
你的头有点大
Your head was a bit large.
四肢有点小
Your arms and legs were a bit small,
却没有爪子
but no claw.
没有红眼睛  双腿间也没有尾巴
No red eye. No tail between your legs.
只有一条粉红色的小鸡鸡
Just a tiny pink cock.
我们难掩失望之情
We didn't try to hide our disappointment.
"这算哪门子怪胎"  我跟瑟曦说
"That's not a monster," I told Cersei.
"就是个普通婴儿"
"That's just a baby."
她却说  "他杀了我母亲"
And she said, "He killed my mother."
然后狠狠地捏住了你的小鸡鸡
And she pinched your little cock so hard,
要不是你老哥出手阻止
I thought she might pull it off.
她真有可能扯下来
Until your brother made her stop.
"有什么关系"  她告诉我们
"It doesn't matter," She told us.
"大家都说他活不长了
"Everyone says he will die soon.
我希望他们没说错
I hope they are right.
他就不配活这么久"
He should not have lived this long."
或早或晚  瑟曦从来都能得偿所愿
Sooner or later, Cersei always gets what she wants.
那我的愿望呢
And what about what I want?
我姐姐和她孩子的公道
Justice for my sister and her children.
你如果想要公道
If you want justice,
那可就来错地方了
you've come to the wrong place.
我不同意
I disagree.
我来的地方太对了
I've come to the perfect place.
我要制裁那些伤害过我的人
I want to bring those who have wronged me to justice.
而那些伤害过我的人  全都在这里
And all those who have wronged me are right here.
我要拿格雷果·克里冈爵士开刀
I will begin with Ser Gregor Clegane,
他杀了我姐姐的孩子们
who killed my sister's children
然后满手鲜血地强奸了她
and then raped her with their blood still on his hands
最后杀害了她
before killing her, too.
我做你的代理骑士
I will be your champion.
你好  罗宾
Hello, Robin.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
搭建我的家  临冬城
I'm building my home, Winterfell.
只是照着记忆搭建
At least I think I am.
我很久都没有回去了
I haven't been back there in a very long time.
你为什么离开
Why did you leave?
说来话长
It's a long story.
我一直待在鹰巢城里
I stay here in the Eyrie.
母亲说路上很危险  我必须保证自己的安全
Mother says it's dangerous on the roads and I have to keep myself safe
因为我是谷地主君
because I'm the Lord of the Vale
而谷地主君是很重要的人
and the Lord of the Vale is a very important person.
是的  你当然很重要
Yes, you certainly are.
你什么时候回去
When will you go back?
大概永远回不去了
Probably never.
我的家人不在那了  有人把它烧了
My family doesn't live there anymore and someone burned it down.
临冬城有月门吗
Does Winterfell have a Moon Door?
恐怕没有
No, I'm afraid not.
城堡不是建在高山上  而是建在平地上
It's not high up in the mountains. It's down on the ground.
听起来好危险
That sounds dangerous.
-那你怎么让人飞呢  -我们不这样做
- How do you make people fly? - We don't.
那你们怎么对付坏人
What do you do with all the bad people
可怕的人和你不喜欢的人呢
and the scary people and the people you don't like?
我从没对他们做过什么
I never did anything with them at all.
在我家那边  女孩子不参与这种事
Girls didn't take part in that where I came from.
我是谷地主君
Well, I'm Lord of the Vale.
等我长大  谁让我不高兴  我就让谁飞
When I grow up, I'll be able to fly anybody who bothers me.
你也可以  等我们结婚了
Or you. When we get married,
你不喜欢谁就告诉我
you can tell me if you don't like somebody
我们就带他们来这里  呼的一下
and then we can bring them back here and, whoosh!
就从月门飞出去了
Right through the Moon Door.
我喜欢那种声音
I like the sound of that.
我们给你的临冬城加个月门吧
Let's put a Moon Door in your Winterfell.
好啊
All right.
可以在这座塔上开一个
It can go in here in this big tower.
当心  你把它毁了
Careful. You've ruined it.
现在我要从头再搭一座了
Now I'm going to have to rebuild the whole thing.
-我没毁  -你毁了
- I didn't ruin it. - You did.
它已经被毁了  就因为没有月门
It was already ruined because it didn't have a Moon Door.
我是在修它
I was fixing it.
推倒了可不叫修东西
Knocking things down isn't fixing them.
-那是毁东西  -我没毁它
- It's ruining them. - I didn't ruin it!
-你真蠢  -我没毁它
- You're being stupid. - I didn't ruin it!
罗宾  对不起  我...
Robin, I'm sorry, I--
孩子们哪
Children.
-我打了他  -我看见了
- I hit him. - Yes, I saw.
我不应该这么做
I shouldn't have done that.
不  他母亲应该管教他
No, his mother should have
早就该管教了
a long time ago.
只当是朝正确的方向迈出了一步吧
Consider it a step in the right direction.
要是他告诉了莱莎姨妈...
If he tells Aunt Lysa...
莱莎姨妈交给我来操心
Let me worry about Aunt Lysa.
我只是想留住那些记忆中的东西
I was trying to remember what everything looked like.
我永远也见不到了
I'll never see it again.
现在和永远之间  有很多事情可能发生
A lot can happen between now and never.
你要是想搭建一个更好的家
If you want to build a better home,
首先必须拆掉旧的
first you must demolish the old one.
你究竟为什么杀死乔佛里
Why did you really kill Joffrey?
告诉我原因
Tell me why.
我对你母亲的爱  你根本无法想象
I loved your mother more than you could ever know.
一旦有了机会  我们如何处置
Given the opportunity, what do we do to those
那些伤害我们心爱之人的家伙
who've hurt the ones we love?
在更好的世界里
In a better world,
在爱可以
one where love
战胜力量与责任的地方
could overcome strength and duty,
你或许就是我的孩子了
you might have been my child.
但我们并不生活在那个世界
But we don't live in that world.
你比她当年还要美得多
You're more beautiful than she ever was.
贝里席大人
Lord Baelish...
叫我培提尔
Call me Petyr.
您想见我  莱莎姨妈
You wanted to see me, Aunt Lysa?
过来  珊莎
Come here, Sansa.
你知道这儿有多高吗
Do you know how far the fall is?
不知道
No.
我也不知道到底多高
Neither do I, precisely.
几百呎吧
Hundreds of feet.
想着就迷人
It's fascinating
从这么高的地方掉下  人撞到石头上会怎样
what happens to bodies when they hit the rocks from such a height.
真正的粉身碎骨
The impact breaks them right apart.
就像鸡蛋掉到地上
Like eggs dropped on the floor.
偶尔有些部位还很完整
Sometimes pieces remain intact.
可以看见脑袋搁在那里
You'll find the head sitting on its own.
每根头发都在
Every hair in place.
蓝眼睛无神地睁着
Blue eyes staring at nothing.
我知道你干了什么
I know what you did.
对不起  莱莎姨妈
I'm so sorry, Aunt Lysa.
我不该对罗宾动手
I never should have hit Robin,
我知错了  我保证以后再也不会了
I know it. I promise it won't happen--
少跟我装模作样  你个这荡妇
Don't be coy with me, you little whore.
你吻了他  你吻了培提尔
You kissed him. You kissed Petyr.
-我没有  您不了解情况  -我看见了
- I didn't. You don't understand. - I saw you.
你别想骗我  我亲眼所见
You can't lie to me because I saw it with my own eyes.
-是他吻我  我推开了  -撒谎
- He kissed me. I pulled away. - Liar!
贱人  他是我的
Whore! He is mine!
我父亲  丈夫和姐姐
My father, my husband, my sister,
那些阻碍过我们的人  现在全都死了
they all stood between us and now they're all dead.
这就是胆敢阻碍培提尔和我的人的下场
That's what happens to people who stand between Petyr and me.
往下看
Look down!
往下看  往下看  往下看
Look down! Look down! Look down!
莱莎
Lysa!
放开她
Let her go.
你想要她
You want her?
要这个没脑子的小孩吗
This empty-headed child?
放开她
Let her go.
她跟她母亲一样  永远不会爱你的
She's just like her mother. She'll never love you.
我为你撒谎
I lied for you.
我为你杀人
I killed for you.
你为什么带她来这里  为什么
Why did you bring her here? Why?
我会把她送走
I'll send her away.
我拿性命发誓
I swear on my life.
我向诸神发誓
I swear to all the gods.
放开她  莱莎
Let her go, Lysa.
噢  我亲爱的妻子
Oh, my sweet wife.
我亲爱的傻妻子啊
My sweet, silly wife.
我这一生只爱过一个女人
I have only loved one woman...
只爱一个
only one,
在我这一生当中
my entire life.
只爱你姐姐
Your sister.